## OWULEZI OSINACHI SAMUEL

Home: 51 Irepodun Street , Ijeshatedo , Surulere , Lagos State

**Telephone**: +2348130544890

**E-mail:** samuel\_owulezi@yahoo.com

**Born:** 16th May 1989

**State:** Isiala Mbano LGA, Imo state

#### **SUMMARY:**

Higly motivated self-taught software developer with a sound knowledge of JavaScript, React Js, Node js, Python, Django framework, SQL and NoSQL (MongoDB) programming languages. To contribute to the development of a highly competitive product, improving user experience, and enhancing both personal and organizational growth.

#### **SKILLS HIGHLIGHT:**

- Sound analytical thinking
- Writing clean and concise codes, frontend and backend
- Querying database , SQL and NoSQL
- Managing of application state using state managers like redux and react hooks
- Ability to understand codes written by other developers
- Knowledge of databases and operating systems
- Ability to learn on the fly

### **TECHNOLOGY STACK:**

My Technology stack includes:

HTML, JavaScript, CSS, BootStrap, ReactJs and React-Redux, Nodejs, Python and Django, MySQL and MongoDB.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE:**

# Software Developer trainee, Omela Solutions, Surulere, Lagos State. September 2019 – January 2020

- Worked with a team of experienced web developer to build an online market place for merchants and customers
- Designed and implement frontend interfaces and backend services to assemble web applications based on user stories.
- Built functional interfaces for mobile-first, dynamic web applications.
- Product testing under development
- Identified and reported bugs in the application

## IT Support, High-Tech Data Systems Limited(HDS), Lagos State. (January 2017 – March 2019)

- Provided client support and technical issue resolution via email, phone and other electronic mediums.
- Provided training to clients in the use of systems and applications.
- Hardware and software configuration as needed.
- Hardware and software troubleshooting.
- Technical documentation and training of End Users

# National Youth Service Corps (NYSC), Bright learners College, Akure, Ondo state. (August 2014 – August 2015)

- Mathematics and Physics Teacher,
- Prepared Students for GCE,WAEC,UTME and Post-UTME.
- Provided home support when required.

### **EDUCATION:**

SCHOOL	COURSE/QUALIFICATION	YEAR OBTAINED
Federal University of Technology Owerri Imo State.	Chemical Engineering B.Eng.	2013
Ijeshatedo Boys Secondary School, Sanya Surulere Lagos.	Senior School Certificate Examination [SSCE].	2004
Innocent Childeren international nursery and Primary School, Lagos.	First leaving School Certificate.	1998

### **INTEREST**

- Learning and Writing Codes
- Reading and Researching
- Soccer
- Cooking

### **REFEREES**

Available on request.